<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Swarm on Andrea Tosatto</title>
    <link>https://www.tosatto.me/tags/swarm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Swarm on Andrea Tosatto</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2016 19:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.tosatto.me/tags/swarm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Engine - From one to hundreds nodes</title>
      <link>https://www.tosatto.me/talks/docker-engine---from-one-to-hundreds-nodes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2016 19:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tosatto.me/talks/docker-engine---from-one-to-hundreds-nodes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The recent DockerCon in Seattle has been really amazing.
Among the many announcements made by the Docker team, for sure the most
incredible one has been the presentation of the new Docker Engine &amp;ldquo;Swarm mode&amp;rdquo;
that will be shipped in Docker 1.12.
This feature has really shocked the container orchestration solutions
community pushing Docker Swarm from a follower technology to be a potential
leader of the competition.
In this talk we will dive into the features of the new Docker Engine &amp;ldquo;Swarm
mode&amp;rdquo; comparing it to the previous implementation of Docker Swarm.
We will also talk about tools and tips to test the &amp;ldquo;Swarm Mode&amp;rdquo; at scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;La recente DockerCon di Seattle è stata veramente incredibile.
Tra la diverse nuove funzionalità e demo mostrate dal team di Docker, senza dubbio
la più incredbile è stata la presentazione dell&amp;rsquo;integrazione tra Docker Swarm
e il Docker Engine che verrà resa disponibile al pubblico per l&amp;rsquo;imminente rilascio
di Docker 1.12.
Questa nuova funzionalità ha mischiato ancora una volta le carte della partita
in corso fra le differenti soluzioni di &amp;ldquo;container orchestration&amp;rdquo; spingend
Docker Swarm dall&amp;rsquo;essere una soluzione &amp;ldquo;follower&amp;rdquo; e immatura, all&amp;rsquo;essere
leader della competizione.
In questo talk esploreremo le nuove funzionalità introdotte dalla &amp;ldquo;Swarm mode&amp;rdquo;
del Docker Engine comparandole con le funzionalità offerte fino ad oggi
da Docker Swarm.
Parleremo inoltre di strumenti e metodologie per testare agilmente le funzionalità
della &amp;ldquo;Swarm mode&amp;rdquo; su cluster con decine di nodi.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>