<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Andrea Tosatto</title>
    <link>http://tosatto.me/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Andrea Tosatto</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 23:30:35 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://tosatto.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Day #1</title>
      <link>http://tosatto.me/posts/day-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 23:30:35 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tosatto.me/posts/day-one/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today is &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;the day one&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: the day in which I&amp;rsquo;m finally kickstarting my personal
website. &lt;br /&gt;
The day zero lasts for many years: looking at its whois records I discovered that
I bought this domain name in the far 2011.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;$ whois tosatto.me
Domain Name: TOSATTO.ME
WHOIS Server:
Referral URL: www.namecheap.com
Updated Date: 2016-08-19T22:50:17Z
Creation Date: 2011-08-19T14:37:20Z
Registry Expiry Date: 2017-08-19T14:37:20Z
# [...]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At that time I was 21 years old, still at University, spending most of the time hacking
exams and code with my incredible colleagues and wondering what I would have been
in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then it came 2012, my third year of University. I was deep in programming languages
and concurrency theory and writing my bachelor thesis,
&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Type for Leak Detection in a Session-Oriented Functional Programming Language&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;.
I was really having fun with such kind of strange topics.
So much that it finally came the first opportunity to use the domain
name I had bought the year before without never using it:
I needed to publish somewhere on the web my thesis in order to let to some external
reviewers to read it and, hopefully, support my candidature for a student grants
to cover the expenses to attend &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://popl.mpi-sws.org/2013/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;POPL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;,
a very huge conference on programming languages theory in Rome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately I didn&amp;rsquo;t won the prize so I&amp;rsquo;ve never been to POPL, but this
is what my website was looking like at that time.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://tosatto.me/img/posts/day-one/tosatto.me.png&#34; alt=&#34;tosatto.me - bachelor degree dissertation&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        tosatto.me - bachelor degree dissertation
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Yes. It was utterly ugly, but it was temporary, just for few weeks: all
the important informations where there, included a super-short presentation of
my work. These were my plans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, my website has been exactly like that until now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now. It&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;2016&lt;/strong&gt;. I still don&amp;rsquo;t know what I will be in my future like in 2011.&lt;br /&gt;
But finally I&amp;rsquo;ve got a real brand new website!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Welcome!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://tosatto.me/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2016 16:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tosatto.me/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Passionate technologist. &lt;br /&gt;
Automation fanboy. &lt;br /&gt;
Head in the cloud. &lt;br /&gt;
Loving containers, micro-services, open-source, Golang and Python. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;System and Platform Operations at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.purpleocean.it&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;PurpleOcean&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;
Code Monkey at &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/opsfactory&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;OpsFactory&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;
Infrastructure at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.witapp.me/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;WIT&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Engine - From one to hundreds nodes</title>
      <link>http://tosatto.me/talks/docker-meetup--docker-engine-from-one-to-hundres-nodes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2016 19:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tosatto.me/talks/docker-meetup--docker-engine-from-one-to-hundres-nodes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The recent DockerCon in Seattle has been really amazing.
Among the many announcements made by the Docker team, for sure the most
incredible one has been the presentation of the new Docker Engine &amp;ldquo;Swarm mode&amp;rdquo;
that will be shipped in Docker 1.12.
This feature has really shocked the container orchestration solutions
community pushing Docker Swarm from a follower technology to be a potential
leader of the competition.
In this talk we will dive into the features of the new Docker Engine &amp;ldquo;Swarm
mode&amp;rdquo; comparing it to the previous implementation of Docker Swarm.
We will also talk about tools and tips to test the &amp;ldquo;Swarm Mode&amp;rdquo; at scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;La recente DockerCon di Seattle è stata veramente incredibile.
Tra la diverse nuove funzionalità e demo mostrate dal team di Docker, senza dubbio
la più incredbile è stata la presentazione dell&amp;rsquo;integrazione tra Docker Swarm
e il Docker Engine che verrà resa disponibile al pubblico per l&amp;rsquo;imminente rilascio
di Docker 1.12.
Questa nuova funzionalità ha mischiato ancora una volta le carte della partita
in corso fra le differenti soluzioni di &amp;ldquo;container orchestration&amp;rdquo; spingend
Docker Swarm dall&amp;rsquo;essere una soluzione &amp;ldquo;follower&amp;rdquo; e immatura, all&amp;rsquo;essere
leader della competizione.
In questo talk esploreremo le nuove funzionalità introdotte dalla &amp;ldquo;Swarm mode&amp;rdquo;
del Docker Engine comparandole con le funzionalità offerte fino ad oggi
da Docker Swarm.
Parleremo inoltre di strumenti e metodologie per testare agilmente le funzionalità
della &amp;ldquo;Swarm mode&amp;rdquo; su cluster con decine di nodi.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to Milano DevOps - What is DevOps</title>
      <link>http://tosatto.me/talks/milano-devops--what-is-devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2016 19:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tosatto.me/talks/milano-devops--what-is-devops/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebScale Infrastructures with Kubernetes and Flannel</title>
      <link>http://tosatto.me/talks/container-day--webscale-infrastructures-with-kubernetes-and-flannel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 14:05:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tosatto.me/talks/container-day--webscale-infrastructures-with-kubernetes-and-flannel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;La capacità di rispondere in poche frazioni di secondo alle richieste degli utenti - indipendentemente dal loro numero - è un fattore determinante per il successo dei servizi sul web. Secondo Amazon,  bastano 100 millisecondi di latenza nella risposta per generare una perdita economica di circa l&amp;rsquo;1% sul fatturato. In base alle statistiche di Google AdWords, inoltre, il 2015 ha sancito l’ufficiale superamento del numero di interazioni mobile rispetto a quelle desktop, con la conseguente riduzione della durata media delle sessioni di navigazione web. In uno scenario di questo tipo, la razionalizzazione dell’utilizzo delle risorse hardware e la capacità di scalare rispetto al numero di utenti sono fattori determinanti per il successo del business. In questo talk racconteremo la nostra esperienza di migrazione di soluzioni e-commerce di tipo enterprise in Magento da un’architettura basata su VM tradizionali ad una di tipo software-defined basata su Kubernetes, Flannel e Docker. Discuteremo, quindi, delle reali difficoltà da noi incontrate nel porting su container di soluzioni in produzione e daremo evidenza di come, alla fine di questo lungo viaggio, i nostri sforzi siano stati concretamente premiati dall’aumento di resilienza, affidabilità e automazione della soluzione finale. A supporto della conversazione, mostreremo i risultati dei benchmark da noi condotti per valutare la scalabilità della nuova architettura presentando delle evidenze delle reali capacità di Kubernetes come strumento di orchestrazione di servizi erogati in Docker container. Concluderemo l’intervento presentando il nostro progetto di distribuzione geografica dei nodi master di Kubernetes facendo uso di reti SD-WAN per garantire performance e continuità di servizio della soluzione.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Docker for Fast and Easy Testing of MariaDB and MaxScale</title>
      <link>http://tosatto.me/talks/percona-live--docker-fast-and-easy-testing-of-mariadb-and-maxscale/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2015 11:20:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tosatto.me/talks/percona-live--docker-fast-and-easy-testing-of-mariadb-and-maxscale/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The ability to replicate the production environment in an isolated
testing environment is a key factor for the success of any
infrastructure (major or minor) component upgrade or replacement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before introducing a new technology and deploying components
into critical infrastructures, the maintainers must have a very deep
knowledge of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To reach this expertise it is really important to build and re-deploy
the testing environment in an easy and fast way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Colt Engine we experienced this situation when we decided to
migrate all our hosting customers from MySQL 5.1 to MariaDB 10.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During this presentation we will show how we used Docker
and docker-compose to replicate our production infrastructure in a testing environment and how we used these technologies to dramatically increase our experience and knowledge around MaxScale.
This speech will presents several real examples of different MaxScale
use cases ranging from authentication to read-write splitting and
about how we automated the provisioning of such configurations with Docker.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>